<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>The Framework Hub</title>
  
  
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="axdsan.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-11-19T19:17:13.618Z</updated>
  <id>axdsan.github.io/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>John Smith</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Diaries of a Framework Hopper - Part 2</title>
    <link href="axdsan.github.io/2017/11/19/Diaries-of-a-Framework-Hopper-Part-2/"/>
    <id>axdsan.github.io/2017/11/19/Diaries-of-a-Framework-Hopper-Part-2/</id>
    <published>2017-11-19T15:08:50.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-19T19:17:13.618Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center"><img src="https://scontent-mia3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/22552552_10155150976972799_1836774033677866773_n.jpg?oh=af1dc87f1c9336f73cab06d4f9da0705&oe=5A9934AF"></div><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">Disclaimer: Dear reader, don&apos;t expect to find a high amount of &quot;high-tech&quot; terms discussed</span><br><span class="line">in this blog, as in the entire site, I&apos;m a self-taught developer not a computer scientist</span><br><span class="line">so go easy on me.</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Wait…-Don’t-tell-me"><a href="#Wait…-Don’t-tell-me" class="headerlink" title="Wait… Don’t tell me!?"></a>Wait… Don’t tell me!?</h1><p>It seemed like for me it was the end with frameworks, django seemed so good and everything but I was missing two things, the deployment thing with django (I know at this point you might be saying, hey deployment is a breeze, but keep in mind I was still a noob back then) and another is that I was looking to get more <code>reactivity</code> within the framework, wanted to have more dynamic things on the websites that I built and I could only get that with AJAX/JQuery, but I’m a very persistent person and I never backdown out of anything so easily, so I kept on going and I needed try other frameworks, it was a must.</p><p>It was at this moment where I think I started to turn into a Framework Hopper, don’t worry if you don’t like reading this much, I will try to be short on this one. I started looking into other Web Frameworks, more specifically I looked into how to do dynamic stuff in the web app / websites I wanted to build, e.g. I wanted to have real-time things, like notifications, more reactivity, etc., etc. So I kept on going with my quest to find my dream framework, my true and ultimate reliable framework that I could finally use for good and live happily ever after, well the thing is that after this, I started looking into javascript frameworks, because of course, that’s what I was looking, so I went on with it… (You know when movies put things like 3 years later, or later that month, or things like that? well I will try to do this here now, for sake of the reader, since I’m not going to put in detail what I did and what I didn’t do, don’t worry I get you) … so in period of weeks I jumped between frameworks like, <a href="https://www.meteor.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">MeteorJS</a>, <a href="https://sailsjs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Sails.js</a>, <a href="https://emberjs.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ember.js</a>, I mean you name it! I literally tried up to the exhaustion.</p><p>So when I finished with all of those I kept on looking for features that could fit my needs, either datastore-wise or other things I was always looking into the frameworks, so, I just was at this point of being like in the limbo, I had cool personal projects I wanted to develop but either when I was using a framework I needed another feature from another framework, or  vice-versa, it was crazy… I couldn’t be happy.</p><h1 id="Suddenly…-A-Framework-That-Could-Change-Everything"><a href="#Suddenly…-A-Framework-That-Could-Change-Everything" class="headerlink" title="Suddenly… A Framework That Could Change Everything?"></a>Suddenly… A Framework That Could Change Everything?</h1><p>At this point I was kinda of experienced with frameworks already, given the fact I tried many of them already I knew basically all the things around the MVC architectural pattern, knew virtually how all of the frameworks that I tried worked,every single template engine they used, I mean I was getting next to be a Framework Evangelist, nah, I’m kidding, but at this point I knew fairily enough about them to stay on float.</p><p>Suddenly, I found <a href="https://angularjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Angular</a>, it was amazing, I started doing my routine, because at that point it was like a routine, look up video tutorials online, written articles, blog posts, Thanks to my friend <a href="https://github.com/javiercordero" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Javier</a> I was able to get access to a really nice online course and I could get my feet wet with that framework, started doing the course at the point of like a couple videos where I started to… Not get the information my brain was supposed to register… It could have been because of the overwhelming amount of information that I plugged into it while learning all the previous frameworks, but I just couldn’t register the things that the instructor was explaining, and I mean I couldn’t! it was if the instructor was speaking gibberish to me, he was using all kinds of, what I call, high-end terms and topics, that I couldn’t just continue with Angular, it was just too much for me, so I needed to step back a bit.</p><p>Because Angular seemed so unreachable for me, it turned out to be my arch-nemesis, and like I said before, I’m a guy that I like to challenge myself, but that was just brutal, I mean Dependency Injection? Services? What the Fudge!? As a self-taught developer I needed to learn these things if even wanted to continue any further with Angular, so I let it in my TODO list.</p><h1 id="And-Then"><a href="#And-Then" class="headerlink" title="And Then..?"></a>And Then..?</h1><p>I found out about <a href="https://laravel.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Laravel</a>… Yes I know, I know! <a href="https://youtu.be/jEI3N9kIyP4?t=7" target="_blank" rel="noopener">another one</a> - but hey! it was in a different realm, Laravel is PHP and well to be honest, I tried PHP in the past and I really liked it, so why not, I changed gears and went for it, but you remember back then when I said that I wanted things to be done more dynamically and such? well turns out that the Laravel community adopted a new front-end framework that worked out-of-the-box, literally plug-n-play, <a href="https://vuejs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">VueJs</a>, when I saw this, and some <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rL-dJcxC8X8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">youtube video</a> about it showing real-time capabilities and I was amazed with it, and not only that, Laravel itself was incredible! I mean you could have a complete authentication system working just by typing in the terminal:</p><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">$ php artisan make:auth</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>That’s it!, that’s it! no more baloney, no more high-end topics, no more… difficult things, Laravel was my ultimate dream framework, and you know what? I stayed with it! ‘til now I’m actually using it because I really love it. So I started doing all my personal projects that were on hold and one of them was to do a clone of AskFm / Sarahah, and I did the prototype in what, like 48 hours? yeah, something that was impossible for me in other frameworks it was so smooth in Laravel, basically that’s it, this is where I’m at right now.</p><h1 id="Closing-Words"><a href="#Closing-Words" class="headerlink" title="Closing Words."></a>Closing Words.</h1><p>I would like to thank you the reader, and I appreciate your time into reading this, I know this is not entirely a pure informational blog, or I won’t probably post here that often, but I do thank you for taking your time into reading this, it means you really liked it and if you didn’t, you can also comment down below and leave your constructive criticism.</p><p>Enjoy your day, night, evening!</p><p><img src="https://media.giphy.com/media/QM5lHSyFjz1XW/giphy.gif" alt=""></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-mia3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/22552552_10155150976972799_1836774033677866773_n.jpg?
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Diaries of a Framework Hopper - Part 1</title>
    <link href="axdsan.github.io/2017/11/18/Diaries-of-a-Framework-Hopper/"/>
    <id>axdsan.github.io/2017/11/18/Diaries-of-a-Framework-Hopper/</id>
    <published>2017-11-18T23:57:34.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-19T15:08:25.356Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center"><img src="https://scontent-mia3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/22552552_10155150976972799_1836774033677866773_n.jpg?oh=af1dc87f1c9336f73cab06d4f9da0705&oe=5A9934AF"></div><figure class="highlight plain"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br><span class="line">2</span><br><span class="line">3</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><span class="line">Disclaimer: Dear reader, don&apos;t expect to find a high amount of &quot;high-tech&quot; terms discussed</span><br><span class="line">in this blog, as in the entire site, I&apos;m a self-taught developer not a computer scientist</span><br><span class="line">so go easy on me.</span><br></pre></td></tr></table></figure><h1 id="Who-I-was-before-getting-into-Frameworks…"><a href="#Who-I-was-before-getting-into-Frameworks…" class="headerlink" title="Who I was before getting into Frameworks…?"></a>Who I was before getting into Frameworks…?</h1><p>…Hmm, a complete and total noob towards that topic, I didn’t even knew what were frameworks in the complete sense of the term… So I jumped right into Web Frameworks… I remember the very first Framework was <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ruby on Rails</a> and I really liked it!</p><p>Well, I knew way back that the <code>MVC</code> architectural pattern was around, but didn’t really paid too much attention to it, until I decided to just go with it and see how it went, since I was a neophyte in the topic and also a self-taught developer, I was really afraid of the terms and things it<br>may throw at me, but despite the fact of my fears, I continued looking into the <code>MVC</code> pattern even more.</p><h1 id="My-first-ever-Web-Framework"><a href="#My-first-ever-Web-Framework" class="headerlink" title="My first ever Web Framework."></a>My first ever Web Framework.</h1><p>Like I mentioned above, I jumped right into <code>RoR</code> because it seemed easy to me. Well, it was all good and I started doing small projects… now I’m somewhat an impatient person, and I get sometimes desperate if I want someting done<br>someway and it can’t be done… So when I kept on going with RoR I saw it was turning to be very tedious to work with, and to develop, why? because, I don’t have a “Dream <a href="https://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=RIG&amp;defid=769942" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Rig</a>“ and I needed to wait like 30 seconds before the<br>server started it was crazy! … OH but wait, there’s more! … after the server loaded I had to wait like 10-20 seconds more until just the <code>hello world</code> example appeared in my browser… so this is where things started to roll back down for me, I started to lose interest in the framework and decided to<br>try something new.</p><h1 id="A-New-Hope"><a href="#A-New-Hope" class="headerlink" title="A New Hope."></a>A New Hope.</h1><p>Yeah, pun intended 🤙 - Anyways, after my newly developed passion with RoR decreased to zero in like a week after using it, I started looking for different alternatives, something that could be fast on my <code>not-so-good-semi-gaming-slash-media-computer</code>, that’s where I kept looking and looking and came across with <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Django</a><br>When I saw the framework and btw made in Python! I couldn’t hold my amazement, it was shining brightly before my eyes, lighting the new hope again for a web framework where I could finally rely on! So what did I do? I guess what anyone would do I quickly stared watching new video tutorials on <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qgGIqRFvFFk&amp;list=PL6gx4Cwl9DGBlmzzFcLgDhKTTfNLfX1IK" target="_blank" rel="noopener">youtube</a> related to Django,<br>started getting known with the framework, etc., etc.</p><p>I even finished that series of video tutorials, the whole thing went cool, I later started even working with <code>CBV</code> in Django that is <a href="https://docs.djangoproject.com/en/1.11/topics/class-based-views/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><code>Class-Based-Views</code></a> which is just another way of doing stuff in your views via classes, instead of plain functions, after all of this, I made a little project based on that one we built, which basically what it was, is like an online lyrics website, where you could have albums, artists, lyrics of course, etc., etc.,<br>So the thing it was when I finished that project, I remember deciding to publish it or host it somewhere, and then… there was the deployment phase, another thing that hit me, what was deployment? how could I do it? also any legals implications for publishing a lyrics website? long-story short, yes you need to have some kind of agency that “licenses” your website in order to have lyrics running on your website because all those lyrics are also copyrighted and a bunch of things that made lose hopes in Django, another cool project I did was a Youtube Video Downloader<br><img src="https://i.imgur.com/BZU5fhq.png" alt=""></p><blockquote><p>  (yes I know, yet another one) but of course this was for sake of developing and improving myself with the framework, also don’t mind the <code>We&#39;re Hiring</code> navigation tab xD</p></blockquote><h1 id="Wait…-Don’t-tell-me"><a href="#Wait…-Don’t-tell-me" class="headerlink" title="Wait… Don’t tell me!?"></a>Wait… Don’t tell me!?</h1><p><code>To Be Continued...</code></p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scontent-mia3-1.xx.fbcdn.net/v/t1.0-9/22552552_10155150976972799_1836774033677866773_n.jpg?
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Wait Am I a Blogger Now!?</title>
    <link href="axdsan.github.io/2017/11/18/Wait-I-m-a-Blogger-Now/"/>
    <id>axdsan.github.io/2017/11/18/Wait-I-m-a-Blogger-Now/</id>
    <published>2017-11-18T23:25:11.000Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-18T23:46:54.695Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div style="text-align:center"><img src="http://i0.kym-cdn.com/photos/images/facebook/000/091/881/tumblr_le3iimRqBr1qe91wdo1_500.jpg"></div><p>…Apparently I am, and I’m here to just say things about Frameworks and to express about them through my own personal eye and from personal experience.</p><p>I welcome you to read and leave constructive messages whenever is required or even if a post seemed worthy of a good laugh or not, you are welcome to leave a constructive comment regarding what you read.</p><p>Hope you like the content I will be uploading and hope you stay around for the while!</p><p>See you at my other posts!</p>]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      
      
        &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i0.kym-cdn.com/photos/images/facebook/000/091/881/tumblr_le3iimRqBr1qe91wdo1_500.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
